Finding Aid for Harlow Olin Whittemore Papers, 1905-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Harlow Olin Whittemore papers
1905-1986
Whittemore, Harlow Olin, 1889-1986.
88141 Aa 2
Landscape architect, professor of landscape architecture at the University of Michigan. Files relating to various Michigan projects, notably in Ann Arbor, Hartland, Hillsdale, and Highland Park; subject files on professional activities; and photographs.
5.5 linear feet in 7 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers of Harlow O. Whittemore (Donor No. 1161 ) were received from Whittemore's daughters, Margaret Whittemore Kelleher and Mrs. Jean Whittemore Sharp in the period 1987-1989.
The collection is open to research.
Harlow Olin Whittemore was born in Tawas City, Michigan, on 28 July 1889. He attended Tawas City High School and was graduated from there in 1905. He received a bachelor of science degree from Alma College in 1909, and taught afterwards both at Highland College in Kansas and Kalamazoo High School before he joined the faculty of the University of Michigan in 1914 as an instructor in landscape design. That same year he earned a master of landscape design degree. In 1916 he married Helen Case. He was promoted to assistant professor in 1920, to associate in 1934, and to full professor and chairman of the Department of Landscape Architecture in 1936, a position which he held until his retirement in 1959. Whittemore also served as Director of the University of Michigan's Nichols Arboretum during the latter period.
During his career, Whittemore was involved in a number of landscape design and planning projects. His most acclaimed project was one he developed in 1936 with colleague Henry S. Curtis for the Huron-Clinton Metropark System. This park system, which developed along the Huron River to where it flows into Lake Erie and along the Clinton River to where it flows into Lake St. Clair, eventually grew to 13 parks in the five county metropolitan Detroit region.
Whittemore also served as a consultant to many Michigan municipalities in the areas of planning and landscape design. He worked in communities such as Hartland, where he was involved, along with J. Robert Crouse of the Cromaine Corporation of Cleveland, Ohio, in the Hartland Area Project of the 1930s, an attempt to create an "ideal" rural community using the village of Hartland as a model. Whittemore also consulted in Ann Arbor, Highland Park, Hillsdale, Sault Ste. Marie, and many other Michigan localities.
He passed away 8 December 1986 at the age of 97.
The papers of Harlow O. Whittemore have been divided into the following series: Projects; Topical Files; Family Papers; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Hartland (Mich.); Highland Park (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.); Landscape architecture.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); University of Michigan. Dept. of Landscape Architecture.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; Whittemore, Harlow Olin, 1889-1986.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Alma College.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Cemeteries.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Schools.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Arborcrest Cemetery (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Battle Creek (Mich.); Brighton (Mich.)--Dams.; Cemeteries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Cheboygan County (Mich.); Dams--Michigan--Brighton.; Demmon House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Dexter (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Michigan--Dexter.; Dwellings--Michigan--Hartland.; Hartland (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Highland Park (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Hillsdale (Mich.)--Streets.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Jackson (Mich.)--Motels.; Jones School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Landscape architecture.; Law Quadrangle (University of Michigan); Mack School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Mackinac Island (Mich.); Mackinac Island (Mich.); Motels--Michigan--Jackson.; Nichols Arboretum (University of Michigan); Parks.; Pictured Rocks (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Streets--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Tappan Junior High School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Tourism.; Traverse City (Mich.); University of Michigan.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Washtenaw Avenue (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Whittemore, Harlow Olin, 1889-1986.; Whitmore family.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Projects, 1923-1981
  The Projects series, 1923-1981, consists of files, subdivided geographically by place and arranged alphabetically, of municipal and private landscape and planning projects in various localities in which Whittemore participated. Michigan cities represented include Ann Arbor, especially Ann Arbor Public Schools and Arborcrest and Washtenong Cemeteries; Hartland, with planning for the Hartland Area Project of the 1930s; Highland Park; and Hillsdale. Material is present on other locations, such as Orchard Lake, Owosso, Sault Ste. Marie, Wayne and others as well, though in lesser amounts.
  - Amasa-Hematite Township School, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor, 1935-1966
    - Arborcrest Cemetery
      - Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
      - Drawings and Sketches (Box 1)
    - Glacier Corporation, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Greater Ann Arbor Research Park, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Huron River Heights Subdivision, 1955-1960 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Michigan League Shakespeare Garden, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Nichols Arboretum, 1955; 1960 (Box 1)
    - Presbyterian Church-Site Plan for Planting, undated (Box 1)
    - Public Schools
      - Pioneer High School, 1955-1958; 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Southeast Elementary School, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Vintage Valley Gateway, undated (Box 1)
    - Washtenong Memorial Park
      - Drawings and Sketches
        - 1935-1937 (Box 1)
        - 1953-1955 (Box 1)
      - General
        - 1954-1961 (Box 1)
          includes some drawings and sketches
        - 1962 (Box 1)
    - YMCA/YWCA, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Battle Creek Health Center, undated (Box 1)
  - Benton Harbor-Jean Klock Park, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Hartland (Hartland Area Project), 1930-1953
    - Architecture, Landscape Design and Interior Decorating Activity-History, 1932-1934 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1930-1940; 1943-1947; 10 folders (Box 1)
    - Cromaine Crafts, 1934 (Box 1)
    - Gannon Tract, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Highway Construction, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - Mill, 1934 (Box 1)
    - Music Hall, 1932; 1935; 1938 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter-Hartland Community Life, April 1937-January 1953 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
    - Schools
      - Calendar, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
      - Primary Consolidation, undated; 1931-1933 (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan Extension Course, 1933-1935 (Box 1)
    - Waldenwoods Farm, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Highland Park, 1942-1949
    - Community Building-Proposal and Study, 1946 (Box 1)
    - History (Box 1)
    - Housing, 1942-1948 (Box 1)
    - Parking (Box 1)
    - Parks and Recreation, 1944-1948 (Box 1)
    - Planning-General, 1942-1948; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Planning Commission
      - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 1)
      - Master Plan, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
      - Preliminary Master Plan, circa 1945 (Box 2)
      - Progress Report, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Schools, 1945-1947 (Box 2)
  - Hillsdale, 1927-1959
    - Baw Beese Lake Development, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Central Business District (Box 2)
    - History (Box 2)
    - Housing (Box 2)
    - Industrial Development Corporation, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Industrial Planning, 1947-1949 (Box 2)
    - Maumee Watershed Conservancy District, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Municipal Government-Survey, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Parking (Box 2)
    - Parks and Recreation, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
    - Planning-General, 1947-1950 (Box 2)
    - Population (Box 2)
    - Schools (includes Hillsdale College), 1927; 1946-1952; 1959; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Transportation (Box 2)
    - Zoning, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Huron-Clinton Metropolitan Authority
    - History (Box 2)
    - Lake Erie Metropark, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Melvindale, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Muskegon Heights, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Orchard Lake, 1953-1958; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Owosso (Alvin M. Bentley Park)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
    - Specifications, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Pittsfield Village, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - Sault Ste. Marie, 1948-1957; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Sugar Island (Chase M. Osborn Preserve), 1945-1958; 1964 (Box 2)
  - Washtenaw County
    - Bruin Lake Boy Scout Camp, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Planning Commission-Parks and Recreation Committee, 1960-1978 (Box 2)
  - Wayne
    - Chamber of Commerce Survey, 1941-1945 (Box 2)
    - Planning-General, 1944-1946; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Topical Files, 1905-1982
  The Topical Files series, 1905-1982, contains a wide variety of subjects. Included are professional organizations related to landscape design and planning, such as the American Institute of Planners - Michigan Chapter, the American Society of Landscape Architects - Michigan Chapter, and the Michigan Horticultural Society. Also included are lecture notes, professional papers for presentations, student papers, and correspondence, personal as well as professional.
  - Alma College, 1905-1909 (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Planners-Michigan Chapter
    - Bylaws, 1967; 1971 (Box 3)
    - Memo, The (Newsletter), 1962 (Box 3)
    - Memoranda, 1962-1966 (Box 3)
    - Planning Law Committee, 1960 (Box 3)
  - American Society of Landscape Architects-Michigan Chapter
    - Constitution, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Council of Fellows History Project, 1977-1982 (Box 3)
    - History, 1969-1971; 1979 (Box 3)
    - Indexing Project
      - Correspondence, 1948-1959 (Box 3)
      - Data and Survey Results, 1955-1959; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor-Area Planning Goals, 1964-1966 (Box 3)
  - Biographical (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Personal
      - undated, 1910-1917 (Box 3)
      - undated, 1956; 1974-1978 (Box 3)
      - 1979-1986 (Box 3)
    - Professional
      - Undated, 1919; 1922-1924 (Box 3)
      - 1925 (Box 3)
      - 1926-1927 (Box 3)
      - 1930-1934 (Box 3)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 3)
      - 1939-1942 (Box 3)
      - 1943-1955 (Box 3)
      - 1957-1965 (Box 3)
  - Detroit-Huron-Clinton Park and Parkway Association-Correspondence, 1939-1946 (Box 3)
  - Diary, Mrs. Harlow (Helen Case) Whittemore, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Dunworkin Club
    - Dow, Alexander, undated (Box 3)
    - Earhart, Harry Boyd, undated (Box 3)
    - Large City vs. Small City, undated (Box 3)
    - Power From the Wind, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Governor's Conference on Recreation, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Great Lakes Industrial Development Conference, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Greening Nursery Co., Monroe-History (Box 3)
  - Highland (Kansas) College (Box 3)
  - Huron River Valley Guide (Federal Writer's Project) (Box 3)
  - Landscape Architecture, University of Michigan, Department of
    - General, 1956-1982 (Box 3)
    - Lecture Notes
      - Landscape Architecture 154, undated (Box 3)
      - Landscape Architecture 150, Fall 1950 (Box 3)
      - Landscape Architecture 151, Fall 1955 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers
      - undated (Box 4)
      - Landscape Architecture 151, 1949 (Box 4)
      - Landscape Architecture 202, June, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Lavanburg Foundation, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Horticultural Society-Prizes and Awards Committee
    - Correspondence and Memoranda
      - 1955-1957 (Box 4)
      - 1958-1960 (Box 4)
      - 1961-1968 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Natural Areas Council, 1959-1960; 1971-1972; 1978 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Society of Planning Officials
    - 1951-1955 (Box 4)
    - 1956 (Box 4)
    - undated, 1959-1965 (Box 4)
  - Open Space Standards, 1956; 1963 (Box 4)
  - Papers and Presentations
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1936-1944 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Papers
      - undated (Box 4)
      - 1928 (Box 4)
      - 1933-1945 (Box 4)
      - 1946 (Box 4)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 4)
      - 1958-1959, 1962; 1964; 1978 (Box 4)
  - Porcupine Mountains Wilderness Association, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Simonds, Ossian Cole (Box 4)
  - Superior Township Civic Association, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
  - Teaidi, Aubrey (Box 4)
  - Upper Peninsula Development Bureau, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
- Family Correspondence
  Family Papers consists of personal letters of Harlow, his wife Helen, daughter Margaret, and various other family members.
  - Harlow O. Whittemore letters
    - To Mother (Jessie Whittemore)
      - Alma College, 1905-June 1909; 5 folders (Box 4)
      - Highland University, Kansas, November 1909-1910 (Box 4)
      - Highland University and Madison, Wisconsin, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
      - 1918-1919, 1925; 1937 (Box 4)
      - To Mother and Father, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
      - To Father (W. F. Whittemore), 1905-1917 (Box 4)
      - To his sisters (Ethel and Bernice) 1905-1906, undated (announcing birth of son) (Box 4)
      - To Grandmother and Vernon (brother?), 1905-1906; 1920 (Box 4)
      - To Helen (wife), undated, 1930; 1937; 1953 (Box 4)
      - To Margaret W. Kelleher (daughter), 1984 (Box 4)
    - Letters written to Harlow from Mother, Father, and Douglas (brother), 1906; 1940 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Materials pertaining to Harlow, circa 1905 (Box 4)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 4)
  - Douglas Whittemore (brother) to Harlow, 1950; 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Bernice and Ethel (sisters) to Harlow, 1905-1906; 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Helen Case Whittemore (wife of Harlow) (Box 5)
    - To Jessie Whittemore, 1914-1941; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Mable Case (mother of Helen) to Helen, 1933; 1946 (Box 5)
    - Family History by Helen C. Whittemore, 1934 (Box 5)
    - Diary of Helen C. Whittemore, 1933-1936 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1904 (Box 5)
  - Margaret W. Kelleher (daughter of Harlow)
    - To Harlow Whittemore, undated, 1969; 1973-1986; 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (includes examples of her art work) (Box 5)
  - Jean W. Sharp (daughter) to Harlow and Helen Whittemore, undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1907; 1936 undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous family, genealogical, fragmentary, etc. (Box 5)
- Photographs, undated; circa 1909-1952
  The Photographs series includes both photographic prints and photographic negatives. The approximately 520 prints are subdivided geographically by place and arranged alphabetically. There are prints for nearly every region of the state, but the heaviest concentration is focused upon Ann Arbor, Hartland, Hillsdale, the Upper Peninsula, and Washtenaw County. The content of the negatives (approximately 650 in number) is the same as that of the photographs. This subseries is also subdivided geographically and arranged alphabetically.
  - Portraits (Box 5)
  - Alma College Life, circa 1909; 1 prints (Box 5)
  - Ann Arbor
    - Arborcrest Cemetery, undated; 15 prints (Box 5)
    - Barton Hills, undated; 7 prints (Box 5)
    - De Forest Farm and Fleming Creek, undated; 9 prints (Box 5)
    - General
      - undated, 8 prints (Box 5)
        (include Demmon House, 1432 Washtenaw)
      - April,1914, 2 prints (Box 5)
    - Huron River
      - Barton Pond, 1935; 3 prints (Box 5)
      - Cedar Bend, undated; 10 prints (Box 5)
      - General, undated; 15 prints (Box 5)
      - Newkirk Farm, undated; 10 prints (Box 5)
      - Portage Lake, undated; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - O.V. Jensen Property, undated; 5 prints (Box 5)
    - Morris E. Popkins Farm, undated; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - Presbyterian Church Site, undated; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - Public Schools-Jones, Mack, and Tappan Schools, March, 1928; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - University of Michigan
      - Landscape Design Department Faculty, undated; 1 prints (Box 5)
      - Law Quadrangle, 1935; 1 prints (Box 5)
      - Nichols Arboretum
        - undated, 7 prints (Box 5)
        - Ice Storm, undated; 4 prints (Box 5)
        - 1937, 3 prints (Box 5)
      - Rooming House Group, 1914; 1 prints (Box 5)
    - Vivian House-Detroit Edison Recreation Home, undated; 1 prints (Box 5)
    - Washtenong Memorial Park-Site Photographs, undated; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Battle Creek-Miscellaneous, October 16, 1927; 25 prints in 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Bay City, undated; 1 prints (Box 5)
  - Beulah-Trapp Celery Farm, May, 1941; 4 prints (Box 5)
  - Brighton-Ore Creek Dam, October, 1940; 4 prints (Box 5)
  - Cheboygan County
    - City of Cheboygan-Miscellaneous, August, 1939; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, September, 1941; 10 prints (Box 5)
  - Detroit
    - Roosevelt and Central High Schools, May, 1930; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - Woodlawn Cemetery, May, 1930; 6 prints (Box 5)
  - Dexter
    - Camp Newkirk, July, 1936; 12 prints (Box 5)
    - Judge Dexter Mansion, undated; 5 prints (Box 5)
  - Flint-Flint Public High School, September, 1936; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Grand Ledge-Riverside Park and Grand River, May-July, 1939; 46 prints in 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Grand Rapids-Garfield Park, undated; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Grayling-Hartwick Pines, October, 1934; 6 prints (Box 5)
  - Grosse Pointe-Gardens and Estates-Longyear Estate, 1934; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Hartland
    - Buildings-Miscellaneous, 1930; 1932; 8 prints (Box 5)
    - Cromaine Crafts Site, August, 1936; 2 prints (Box 5)
    - J. Robert Crouse Farm, ca., 1937; 12 prints (Box 5)
    - Deerfield Center School, 1937; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - Millpond Dam, September, 1940; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - Recreation Hall, April, 1940; 2 prints (Box 5)
  - Higgins Lake State Park, July, 1934; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Highland Park,-undated, 6 prints (Box 5)
  - Hillsdale
    - Baw Beese Lake, circa 1949-1952; 2 prints (Box 5)
    - Factory, May, 1941; 1 prints (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1949-1952; 6 prints (Box 5)
    - Street Scenes, circa 1949-1952; 39 prints in 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Holland,(Michigan), Summer 1940; 10 prints (Box 5)
  - Hubbard Lake, circa 1930-1933; 5 prints (Box 5)
  - Huron-Clinton Parkway-Kent Lake Area, undated; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Jackson
    - Jackson High School, May, 1930; 2 prints (Box 5)
    - Oakdale Cemetery, October, 1937; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - Tourist Lodges, July, 1940; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Litchfield-Stock Farm, 1941; 1 prints (Box 5)
  - Ludington-State Park
    - October, 1934, 9 prints (Box 5)
    - May, 1941, 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Mackinac Island
    - Or, 1926; 1937; 5 prints (Box 5)
    - August, 1940, 8 prints (Box 5)
    - Landscape Architecture 153 Field Trip, July, 1946; 9 prints (Box 5)
  - Manistee-Infirmary Garden, May, 1941; 4 prints (Box 5)
  - Marshall, Summer 1941; 2 prints (Box 5)
  - Milford-Huron River, 1937; 1 prints (Box 5)
  - Owosso-Welch Farm, 1915; 2 prints (Box 5)
  - Redford Township-Thurston High School, undated; 3 prints (Box 5)
  - Traverse city, May, 1941; 7 prints (Box 5)
  - Upper Peninsula
    - Chippewa County-Munuskong Bay, 1933; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - Drummond Is, September, 1934; 2 prints (Box 5)
    - Isle Royale, August, 1936; 10 prints (Box 5)
    - Marquette, September, 1936; 5 prints (Box 5)
    - Munising, September, 1930; 28 prints in 2 folders (Box 5)
    - St. Ignace, 1935; 2 prints (Box 5)
    - Sault Ste. Marie
      - Park, July 4, 1926; 1 prints (Box 5)
      - Public Schools, circa 1951; 5 prints (Box 5)
    - Sugar Is, August, 1936; 2 prints (Box 5)
    - Tahquamenon Falls, 1934; 4 prints (Box 5)
  - Washtenaw County
    - Cassidy Lake, 1934; 1 prints (Box 5)
    - Huron River-Delhi, 1936; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - Lincoln Consolidated, undated; 7 prints (Box 5)
    - Pennington School, undated; 4 prints (Box 5)
    - Sharon Hollow Region, 1935; 1 prints (Box 5)
  - Waterloo-Camp Takona, undated; 4 prints (Box 5)
  - Wayne County-Dearborn Ford Rouge Plant, undated; 2 prints (Box 5)
  - Ypsilanti
    - Ford Lake and Dam, undated; 3 prints (Box 5)
    - Normal School, undated; 2 prints (Box 5)
  - Negatives, 8 x 9 3/4 and 3 1/2 x 5 1/2
    - Ann Arbor
      - Arborcrest Cemetery, undated; 2 negatives (Box 5)
      - Washtenong Memorial Park, December, 1952; 1 negatives (Box 5)
    - Highland Park, undated; 5 negatives (Box 5)
    - Hillsdale
      - Baw Beese Lake, circa 1949-1952; 1 negatives (Box 5)
      - Street Scenes, circa, 1949-1952; 36 negatives in 2 folders (Box 5)
        (see box 6 for nos. 1-3)
  - Negatives, 2 1/2 x 3 1/2; and 2 3/4 x 4 1/2
    - Alma College Life, circa 1909; 15 negatives (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor
      (see also larger negatives in box 5)
      - Barton Hills, undated; 7 negatives (Box 6)
      - De Forest Farm and Fleming Creek, undated; 9 negatives (Box 6)
      - Dunman Property, December 31, 1925; 10 negatives (Box 6)
      - General
        - Undated, 8 negatives (Box 6)
        - April, 1914, 4 negatives (Box 6)
      - Huron River (Box 6)
      - Barton Pond, undated; 5 negatives (Box 6)
      - Cedar Bend, undated; 5 negatives (Box 6)
      - General, undated; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - Newkirk Farm, undated; 9 negatives (Box 6)
      - Huron Valley, 1915 (Box 6)
      - James Inglis Property, 1927; 8 negatives (Box 6)
      - O.V. Jensen Property-Granger Avenue, undated; 8 negatives (Box 6)
      - Packard Street-Farm Yard, 1915; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - Morris E. Popkins Farm, undated; 4 negatives (Box 6)
      - Portage Lake, undated; 4 negatives (Box 6)
      - Presbyterian Church Site, undated; 6 negatives (Box 6)
      - Public Schools
        - Jones, Mack, Tappan, March 1928; 5 negatives (Box 6)
        - Tappan, September, 1936; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - Third Woods, 1915; 5 negatives (Box 6)
      - University of Michigan
        - Clements Library Construction, undated; 4 negatives (Box 6)
        - General, undated; 2 negatives (Box 6)
        - Law Quadrangle, 1935; 1 negatives (Box 6)
        - Nichols Arboretum
          - undated, 8 negatives (Box 6)
          - Ice Storm, undated; 4 negatives (Box 6)
        - Rooming House Group, 1914; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Vivian House-Detroit Edison Recreation Home, undated; 2 negatives (Box 6)
    - Battle Creek-Miscellaneous, October 16, 1927; 25 negatives (Box 6)
    - Beulah-Trapp Celery Farm, May, 1941; 3 negatives (Box 6)
    - Birmingham, 1937; 5 negatives (Box 6)
    - Brighton
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Ore Creek Dam, October, 1940; 3 negatives (Box 6)
    - Cheboygan County
      - Black River Ranch, undated; 5 negatives (Box 6)
      - City of Cheboygan
        - Miscellaneous, August, 1939; 3 negatives (Box 6)
        - Music Camp, undated; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Indian River, undated; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - Methodist Children's Camp, undated; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous
        - undated, 2 negatives (Box 6)
        - September, 1941, 11 negatives (Box 6)
      - Shanty Rapids, undated; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - Wolverine Cemetery, 1937; 2 negatives (Box 6)
    - Detroit
      - Roosevelt and Central High Schools, May 1930; 7 negatives (Box 6)
      - Woodlawn Cemetery, May, 1930; 10 negatives (Box 6)
    - Dexter
      - Camp Newkirk, July, 1936; 12 negatives (Box 6)
      - Dexter Huron Park, 1935; 6 negatives (Box 6)
      - Judge Dexter Mansion, undated; 5 negatives (Box 6)
    - Flint-Flint Public High School, September 1936; 13 negatives (Box 6)
    - Glen Haven-State Park, undated; 2 negatives (Box 6)
    - Grand Haven, undated; 1 negatives (Box 6)
    - Grand Ledge
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 negatives (Box 6)
      - Riverside Park and Grand River, May-July, 1939; 12 negatives (Box 6)
    - Grand Rapids Garfield Park, undated; 10 negatives (Box 6)
    - Grosse Pointe Estates and Gardens-Longyear Estate, 1934; 3 negatives (Box 6)
    - Harrisville, 1924; 1 negatives (Box 6)
    - Hartland
      - Buildings
        - 1930, 18 negatives (Box 6)
        - 1932, 4 negatives (Box 6)
      - Cromaine Crafts Site, August, 1936; 2 negatives (Box 6)
      - J. Robert Crouse Farm, circa 1937; 12 negatives (Box 6)